Daniel M. Brown 12534 Clearview Lane

Indianapolis, IN 46236 Home: (317)855-7720 Mobile: (317) 989-3895 danbrown1009@yahoo.com

Profile: An interactive, creative educator with excellent communication and organizational skills. My experiences have given me the opportunity to teach lessons in various types of communities, and have helped me in being more diverse with my lesson planning at the secondary level. I also have a considerable background in theater/drama, audio/visual equipment, video production for school newscasts, and have assisted in coaching youth baseball, and Junior High wrestling.

Education:

Indiana University Northwest *Gary, Indiana*.

Bachelor of Science, Secondary Education (5/2005)

IUPUI Indianapolis, Indiana

Graduate level classes in Economics (6 credits)

Certification:

State of Indiana Secondary Education Teaching License Grades 5-12

Primary Concentration: US History; Secondary Concentration: World History, and Political Science

Field Experiences: Developed and taught lessons at the following schools

Lowell Alternative High School (Lowell, IN)

Scott Middle School (Hammond, IN.)

Fegely Middle School (Portage, IN)

Hanover Central High School (Cedar Lake, IN.)

Student Teaching:

Fegely Middle School

Portage, Indiana. (1/2005-4/2005)

Developed creative lessons that encouraged student involvement, while meeting state standards

Taught Social Studies to 8th grade students

Managed classroom of 22-26 students

Participated in teacher in-service days

Used various types of media technology to present lessons and to allow students to complete projects.

Worked with other teachers as a team to develop lessons that would cross-reference in other subject content areas.

Participated in teacher/parent conferences.

Substitute Teacher:

Tri-Creek School Corporation, Lowell Indiana

Portage Township School Corporation, Portage Indiana.

August 2001-June 2005

Computer Skills

MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Movie maker, Adobe Premiere Studio, Internet, E-mail, Campus Vue, Google Chrome, Blendspace, Prezi

Professional Experience:

Middle School Social Studies Teacher:

MSD Warren Township Renaissance School 8931 East 30th St. Indianapolis Indiana 46219 July 2013-Present

Managed classrooms of 7th, and 8th grade "at risk" students in an alternative school setting.. Developed and executed lesson plans that were relevant to state and CORE standards. Worked with "at risk" students to improve behavior and life social skills. Established professional relationships with faculty, staff, and families. Member of the PBIS (Positive Behavior Intervention Support) team.

Director of Admissions:

Sanford-Brown College 4030 Vincennes Rd Indianapolis, IN 46268 October 2011-April 2012

Advised and enrolled students in educational programs in a variety of fields. Provided student support to those enrolled after classes began.

Assistant Director of Admissions:

Brown Mackie College 1000 E. 80th Place Merrillville, Indiana 46410 August 2010-October 2011

Conducted interviews and tours with prospective students.
Assisted students through the application and enrollment processes.
Provided student support to those enrolled after classes began.
Assisted in coordinating new student orientation

Middle School Social Studies Teacher:

Nativity Catholic School 3310 S. Meadow Dr. Indianapolis Indiana 46239 August 2007-August 2010

> Managed classrooms of 6th, 7th, and 8th grade students Developed and executed lesson plans that were relevant to state standards. Engaged in learning experience with students Assisted with after school activities Established professional relationships with faculty, staff, and families. Member of the Disciplinary Action Committee

Permanent Building Substitute:

Hamilton Southeastern Junior High School 12001 Olio Road. Fishers Indiana 46037 August 2006-June 2007

Managed classrooms of 7th and 8th grade students
Developed emergency lesson plans, when plans were not available.
Assisted in coaching middle school wrestling
Engaged in learning experience with students
Established professional relationships with Faculty and Staff
Directed audio/visual club, and produced a bi-weekly television show.

References:

Matt Dingman 8931 E. 30th St. Indianapolis, IN 46219 (317) 532-2993

mdingman@warren.k12.in.us

Position: Director of Alternative Education/Principal of Renaissance School MSD Warren

Terri Rodriguez 3310 S. Meadow Dr. Indianapolis, IN 46239 (317)357-1459

trodriguez@nativityindy.org

Position: Principal of Nativity Catholic School

Mike McLindon 3286 Rustic Lane Crown Point, IN 46307 (219) 613-8257 mmclindon@tricreek.k12.in.us Position: Social Studies teacher

Deb Fersch 7026 Royal Oakland Way Indianapolis, IN 46236 (317) 679-1221 dfersch@warren.k12.in.us

Position: Dean of Students of Renaissance School MSD Warren

Kara Hipskind 5802 Evanston Ave Indianapolis, IN 46220 (317) 371-3310 khipskind@warren.k12.in.us

Position: Guidance Counselor

Sean Watson 5440 west 16th street Speedway, IN 46224 (317) 402-7722 swatson3@warren.k12.in.us

Position: Special Education Teacher

Linda White 11118 Deer Valley Dr. Indianapolis IN 46229 (317) 946-8027 lindawhte@juno.com

Position: Science Teacher

Howard A. Dorsey, Jr. 2434 Constellation Drive Indianapolis, IN 46229 317 899-1305

hdorsey@warren.k12.in.us

Position: Dean of Students of Renaissance School MSD Warren

Mark Marvin 3297 North 400 East Monticello, IN 47960 (219) 242-5612

mmarvin@portage.k12.in.us

Position: Supervising teacher for student teaching